We are now inside a MATLAB environment. And we are going to be using MATLAB to
我们现在进入了 MATLAB 的工作环境 我们将使用MATLAB来
illustrate some of these picture modification, algorithm we just described
演示一些的像素修正的例子 其中用到了我们刚提到的算法
and also some those are we are going to see in the next video.
也用到了我们在下一个视频中要讲到的算法
MATLAB is a great software to do image processing.
MATLAB 是一个做图像处理的非常好用的软件
Of course, you don't need to have MATLAB to understand what I'm, going to show you
当然 即使你没有 MATLAB 或者不知道怎么在 MATLAB 中编程
next or you don't need to know how to program in MATLAB.
也能明白接下来的演示
It's very intuitive and it's going to be very simple for us to understand the
我的演示非常直观 理解我接下来的操作命令也非常容易
commands that I'm going to do. The first command, is basically reading
第一个操作命令 就是简单地读入一幅图像
an image. As we see here, we are reading the image.
可以看到 我们正在读入图像
The next command is going to have a number of steps, which I'm going to show
下一个操作命令将有一系列步骤 我将一一展示给你们
you next. I'm going to first, create a figure and
首先 创建一个图形窗口
show the image in that figure. Then I create a second figure, and I'm
然后把图像显示在里面 之后我要创建第二个图形窗口
going to show you the histogram of that image.
来显示那个图像的直方图
And I'm going to keep creating figures to illustrate the other operations, I want
我将创建许多个图形窗口来展示其它操作的结果
to show you. One of them is going to be the inversion
其中一个窗口是反色后的图像
of that image, 255 minus I.
255 减去 I
And the last thing I want to show you is the histogram of that image.
最后展示的是这个反转图像的直方图
You can start thinking, how the histogram of the inversion compares to the
你们可以想想 反转图像的直方图
histogram of the original image. Let's see that.,
与原来的有什么区别 我们一起来看看
let's just show all those figures, one after the other, I'm going to move them,
让我们显示出所有图形窗口 一个挨着一个 我要移动它们
so it makes it easier for us to observe those images, those figures.
这样我们就能很轻松地观察这些图像
And I'm going to tell you what each one of them is.
我会告诉你们它们每一个都是什么
So here is the original image. And this is its histogram.
这是原始图像 这个是它的直方图
And we see the image is pretty dark, so we see a large concentration of dark
可以看到这个图像很暗 所以直方图中像素值大多集中在深色值区域
values. Here is the inversion of the image.
这是反色后的图像
We basically have flip all of image values.
我们把图像所有的值都反转了
And look what happened to the histogram. The histogram also has flip.
那么看看直方图有什么变化 直方图也反转了
Basically, what was here, it moved to here as we have expected
基本上 曾经在这里的 如我们所想 移动到了这里
because we are just flipping the pixels we are not making any other change but
因为我们仅仅反转了像素值 并没有做其它改动
flipping the pixel values. So it's a very simple operation and we
所以这是一个很简单的操作
see what's happening to the histogram. Let's now see another operation that we
并且我们看到了直方图上的相应变化 让我们看看另一种操作
are going to describe in detail in the next video.
我们将在下一个视频中详细介绍它
And it's going to be an what's called histogram equalization.
也就是所谓的直方图均衡
I'm going to look for the command to do the histogram equalization and to show
我要查询下能完成直方图均衡化的命令
that to you. And that's going to be here.
并展示给你们 就在这里
Once again, I'm going to show you the image and its histogram as before.
再一次地 我将把原图像和它的直方图显示在这
Now I'm going to show you the equalized image and I'm going to illustrate what
现在我要显示的是均衡化后的图像 我将演示给你们这对于图像和直方图
that means and also the histogram. So again we're going to have four
各意味着什么 那么同样我们有4张图像
figures. And, I think that you are starting to
我想你们已经开始猜测会发生什么
guess what's happening here. As before, we have the original image,
和以前一样 我们有原始图像
it's historgram We see the histogram very concentrated on the left.
和它的直方图 我们看到它的直方图中数值集中在左侧
Here we have the result what's called histogram equalization.
这里我们有经过直方图均衡化后的结果
What we are trying to do here is to make this histogram looks more uniform.
我们希望做的是让直方图看起来更均衡
Look at here, how instead of being concentrated in the low values, showing
看这里 不再是集中在较低的值附近——
that this is a very dark image. We spread the pixel's values so there is
表示这是一幅非常暗的图像 我们把像素值分散开来
better exploitation of all the gamut of values from zero to 256.
以期更好地利用 0到256 的取值范围
Instead of here that there was almost no pixels with this value.
不再像这儿 几乎没有像素是这个像素值
That is to come equalization help us to see details that we couldn't see before
由此达到了均衡化 这也让我们可以看清之前不可见的细节
like this region of the tire. So it's a very powerful operation to be
譬如轮胎的这个区域 所以这是一种非常有用的操作
able to basically see details in the image that because of the bad use of the
有它我们可以看清图像中 因没有充分利用灰度谱
spectrum of grey values we couldn't see before.
而让人之前无法看清的细节
What we're going to see next is how we actually mathematically do this
我们接下来要做的是看看 如何在数学上实现这种操作
operation. So, see you in the next video.
那么 下一个视频再见 // 果壳教育无边界字幕组 | 昵称不定 | 玉米Yummy | 小白_远游